# Vitali Zaidman

I'm a Senior Software Engineer with broad experience in hands-on coding, architecture design, helping C-suite management make good decisions, and leading teams to success.

I'm also a React.js expert with open-source contributions and publications about web development.

#### **EDUCATION**

# The Open University of Israel—

**2010 - 2014** — BS.c Computer Science

Completed computer science courses such as data structures, algorithmics, networking, AI, encryption and discrete, infinitesimal, and analytic mathematics.

Moving to London, UK Global Talent Visa Holder +972-547-777-983 vzaidman@gmail.com

vzaidman.com medium.com/@vzaidman linkedin.com/in/vzaidman twitter.com/vzaidman

#### **MAIN SKILLS**

JavaScript, TypeScript, React.js, Redux.js, Next.js, Lerna, Babel, Webpack, Node.js, Jest, SEO, Storybook, SCRUM, Git, CI/CD, Article writing, Azure, AWS

#### **LANGUAGES**

English, Russian, Hebrew

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# 2018 - 2021 — Hands On Software Architect in 10bis.co.il (part of Just Eat Takeaway.com) —

(React.js, Node.js, Next.js, SEO, Azure Cloud, Azure Pipelines)

10bis.co.il is the largest food-delivery service in Israel with 500,000 customers and more than 5,000 restaurants.

Lately, it was acquired by the worldwide Just Eat Takeaway.com for 157 million dollars.

- Led a team of 5 developers in the re-building, from scratch, of <u>10bis.co.il</u> using the latest web technologies, and the further development of the website.
- Guiding other departments regarding integrations on the website- improved the traffic to the website from Google, working with the SEO and analytics teams.
- Was responsible for the infrastructure of the project- 3rd party packages, Webpack, Babel, Azure Pipelines.
- Reported to the CTO.

Simultaneously, led another team of 4 developers in the creation of <u>TakeawayPay</u>, a unique innovation in the food delivery industry. The platform enables companies to register online and issue food ordering allowances to their employees. This very exciting project grew into a worldwide sensation quickly, serving 9 (soon 13) countries.

## 2016 - 2018 — Technical Team Lead in Powtoon.com —

(Math, React, Redux, Typescript, StoryBook, Bitbucket CI, AWS)

A start-up that provides a platform to create cloud-based presentations and animated videos on the browser.

PowToon had 10 million users in 2016 and has more than 30 million users today.

- Led a team of 8 developers in the rebuilding of the PowToon animation studio, from the ground up, in less than a year and led the further development of the product.
- Managed the company's technological transformation from a Flash (ActionScript) based product to React.js including the tutoring of the company's developers who were new to these new technologies.
- Implemented the mathematics that is behind the animations in the project.
- Made a lot of decisions about the product's direction in its new form.
- Was responsible for the infrastructure of the project- 3rd party packages, Webpack, Babel, Azure Pipelines.
- Reported to the CTO.

## WellDone Software Solutions Ltd.—

A boutique software solutions company is known as a company that fosters a culture of excellence and implements the best software solutions for the companies that it works with.

## 2016 - 2021 — Software Architect, Technical Publisher, Senior Management Member

- Led teams in web projects (10bis.co.il and PowToon).
- Introduced the horizontal working principle whereby architects from different projects consult and even work
  for weeks on the other projects to generate insights for all the parties involved, thus maintaining a large body
  of knowledge regarding software solutions and the latest technologies.
- Published many articles / maintained open source projects on behalf of the company.
- Worked directly with the CEO.

## 2012 - 2016 — Full-Stack Developer, Mobile Developer

(JavaScript, Node.js, MongoDB, Angular, React.js, Sencha, Cordova, Android, iOS, Windows Phone, PHP, SQL)

Worked on a variety of start-ups, developing front-ends, back-ends, databases, and mobile applications.

#### **OPEN SOURCE CONTRIBUTIONS**

See more at vzaidman.com#open-source

#### Why Did You Render —

With **1,000,000 downloads a month**, this is the most salient library for monitoring and improving **React** performance.

I founded the library in 2018 and still actively maintain and update it.

### WEBINAR AND CONFERENCE LECTURES

More at vzaidman.com#meetup-videos.

Takeaway.com webinar - Do You Need Server Side Rendering? What Are The Alternatives?

Takeaway.com Webinar - Advanced React - Virtual DOM and Performance

<u>Lecture at the Israeli Architecture Next 2020 Conference - Do You Need Server Side Rendering? What Are The Alternatives? (in Hebrew)</u>

#### **PODCASTS**

More at vzaidman.com#podcasts

React Round-Up 087: Why Did You Render and React Performance

JavaScript Jabber 402: SEO for Developers

My JavaScript Story 098: Vitali Zaidman

JavaScript Jabber 331: "An Overview of JavaScript Testing in 2018" with Vitali Zaidman

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

## An Overview of JavaScript Testing 2017 - 2021

A series of articles that got over 800,000 views about JavaScript testing.

Each article covers the latest state of JavaScript Testing for several years, from the basics of testing to the most prominent available technologies in the field:

- An Overview of JavaScript Testing in 2017
- An Overview of JavaScript Testing in 2018
- An Overview of JavaScript Testing in 2019
- An Overview of JavaScript Testing in 2020 2021

# A Series of Articles About The "Why Did You Render" Library

A series of articles about my open-source library, Why Did You Render, that got over 120,000 views:

- Track Redundant React Hooks Re-Renders With "Why Did You Render" Version 3
- Track React-Redux Redundant Re-Renders With "Why Did You Render" Version 3
- Why Did You Render Mr. Big Pure React Component?
- Why Did You Render Mr. Big Pure React Component? Part 2- Common Fixing Scenarios
- Why Did You Render v4 Released!

## Articles with more than 10,000 views:

An Overview of Developer Tools for Windows Jul 28, 2017 —

An overview of developer tools for Windows.

Babel.js Guide -Part 1- The Absolute Must-Know Basics: Plugins, Presets, And Config Jul 04, 2019 —

What is Babel, and how to use it? What are "presets" and "plugins", and in what order does Babel apply them?

CSS Theme Organization Best Practices Jul 23, 2019 —

The three levels of theme abstraction that will make your CSS themes invincible.

# Articles with more than 5.000 views:

useCallback Might Be What You Meant By useRef & useEffect Jan 14, 2021 —

Sometimes we respond to React element mounts.

The first instinct is to useRef & useEffect, but It's wrong. What you really need is often useCallback.

redux-toolbelt: Supercharge Your Redux Feb 3, 2018 —

10x less code, 10x more redux power - part 2 - the basics.

More publications at vzaidman.com#publications